Sheet music collection on medical themes
Medical Historical Library, Harvey Cushing / John Hay Whitney Medical Library
- Individual Songs in French by title, 2.
  - Small format, 19th century - 1971 (Box 9)
    - Elixir Lagane: chanson des coutteux
      Words by Jehan Madelaine, music by F. Matz Ferrare. One leaf – may be incomplete. No publication information. Dedicated to Lucien Lagane, "Pharmacien a Bordeaux." Performed by A. Guillemot of the Grand-Théatre de Bordeuax. Image of a bottle, words indistinct, and men drinking and hanging up their crutches. Elixir Lagane appears to be a fictional cure-all.
    - Elle avait un p'tit cad'nas!: chanson d'actualité
      Words by Valentin Pannetier and Marcel Désautés. Paris: V. Pannetier, Editeur, n.d. Words only. Cover image of a Satanic figure unlocking a lock around the waist, wrists, and genitals of a naked woman.
    - Elle est anémique
      Words by Henry Moreau and Plébus, music by Vincent Scotto. Paris: Marcel Labbé, Editeur, n.d. (20th cent.) First performed by Alibert. Cover lists many others who have performed the piece.
    - L'Embryoscope
      Words only to be sung to the tune of "C'était une fille" by Gabaroche. Words by Gabriello. Paris: The author, n.d. Performed by the author at the "Cabaret des Quat' z' Arts." List of several other performers and theaters. The "embryoscope" is an imaginary instrument which determines if the fetus is a boy or a girl.
    - Une Erreur
      One leaf only. Incomplete. Words by Martial Vergnolle, music by Barret. Paris: Pitau, Editeur, n.d. Cover image of a man administering a clyster to a patient in a military hospital bed. Performed by Sulbac at the Eldorado, and by St. Bonnet.
    - Etude sur le corps: scène comique
      Words only. Single leaf. Words and music by Saint-Gilles and Briollet. No publication information. On the human body.
    - Femmes que vous êtes jolies!
      Words by E. Favart, music by P. Codini. Paris: Aux Editions L. Codini, F. Galifer, & Julsam, n.d. Cover image of a Red Cross nurse tending a soldier on the battlefield
    - La Formule "606"
      Words only. Words by Valentin Pannetier and Marcel Hamel, music by Vincent Scotto. Paris: Valentin Pannetier, Editeur, n.d. (20th cent.) 606 refers to Paul Ehrlich's treatment for syphilis. Image of a man before and after the inoculation. List of various performers and theaters.
    - Fumeur d'opium
      Words by Mortreuil and Joullot, music by Helmer. Paris: Marcel Labbé, Editeur, n.d. Performed by Bérard at the Eldorado, and others at various theaters.
    - Le Garçon apothicaire
      Words by Victor Gresset, music by Constant Dhorn. From Le Cri-Cri: Revue bi-mensuelle de la chanson française, Paris, n.d.
    - Le Garçon pharmacien
      Words by E. Gitral and J. Bertet, music by Vincent Scotto. Paris: Vincent Scotto, Compositeur Editeur, c. 1924. Performed by Alibert at the Olympia.
    - Les Gaz hilarants
      Words by C. Collet and E. Gibert, music by Laurent Halet. Paris: Laurent Halet, n.d. Recorded by Constantin on various record labels.
    - Gloire à Pasteur!
      Words by Emile Cheret, music by Ed. Deconclois. Paris: F. Bigot, Editeur, n.d. Song in praise of Louis Pasteur. Performed by Marius Richard at la Scala. Image of Pasteur and various scenes related to him on the cover, and a banner with the label "Institut Pasteur."
    - L'Hirondelle du Faubourg
      Words and music by L. Benech and E. Dumont. Copyright L. Benech, Paris, 1913. Performed by Dona. Cover image is of a doctor and nurse at the hospital bedside of a young girl.
    - Il a l'influenza
      Words and music by Emile Duhem. Originally Published by S. Patay, Paris. Words only. Single sheet probably extracted from a contemporary magazine on French songs.
    - L'Inoculation
      Words by Saint-Gilles and Briolet, music by Saint Gilles. Words only. From Recueil de douze monologues et scènes comiques, No. 6, pp. 5-6. Paris: Les Editions Jean Picot, n.d. (20th cent.). Song refers to inoculation with glandular extracts for rejuvenation. Another medically themed song in the issue is "A bas les légumes" by Saint-Gilles and P. Briollet.
    - Les Infirmières de France
      Words by A. Gremillet (called Gervy), music by P. Codini. Paris: P. Codini, Compositeur-Editeur, c. 1916. Performed by Vorelli. Cover image of a Red Cross nurse in a heart-shaped frame.
    - J'ai le phylloxéra: chanson maladive
      Words by Plébius and Mauban, music by Emile Spencer. Paris: G. Siévier, Editeur, n.d. Performed by Chevailier at the Cigale, and by others at other theaters.
    - J'ai l'ténia
      Words by Louis Chautard, music by Alfred Séguin. Paris: Louis Aerts, Editeur, n.d. Performed by Marcel Montel.
    - J'aime pas ces plaisant'ries là
      Words by Villemer and Delormel, music by Ch. Pourny. Paris: S. Bornemann, Editeur, n.d. Performed by Victorin at the Eldorado. Cover has several images including a man being chased by a flying clyster.
    - Je n'suis pas bien portant
      Words by Géo Koger, music by Vincent Scotto and Ouvrard. Paris: E. Bousquet, Editeur, c. 1932. Performed by Ouvrard. Music and patter.
    - Je suis malade
      Words by Serge Lama, music by Alice Doma. Paris: Plein Soleil and Bagatelle Editions Musicales, c. 1971. Recorded by Sergh Lama on Disques Philips.
    - Je suis vaseux
      Words by Maubon and Haldy, music by E. Spencer. Prais: Bertal-Maubon, c. 1912. "Répertoire Bertal-Maubon." Performed by Montel at the Eldorado.
    - Les jours se suivent
      Words by A. Isch Wall, music by Gustave Chaillier. Paris: Bathlot, Editeur, n.d. (19th cent.) Sung by Gustave Chaillier at the Eldorado. Cover image of a servant bringing a clyster to a wealthy man wearing a robe and slippers.
    - Le Joyeux malade: scène comique
      Spoken words, no music. Words by Jean Péheu and Denola. Paris: L. Maurel (M.D.), Editeur, n.d. Performed by Darius M. at the Parisiana, and by various other performers at other theaters.
    - Jû û ûles!!!, ou les étapes amoureuses d'un gommeux pharmacien
      Words by Jules Dumont, music by Edmond Potier. Paris: J. Dumont, Editeur, n.d. Song and spoken words performed by Mme. Mandarine at the Ambassadeurs.
    - Le Lavement au bouillon gras, ou la peur d'être cocu
      Recitation, no music. Paris: Bassereau, Editeur, n.d. Performed by Villemer. Color lithograph on cover of a boy and an older woman exchanging a huge clyster.
    - Ma temperature
      Words by Belhiatus and Rimbault, music by Emile Spencer. Paris: Delormel & Cie, Editeurs, n.d. (early 20th cent.).
    - Maigrir!...(tango)
      Words by JAN, Music by JIL. Copyright 1959 by Les Nouvelles Editions Meridian, Paris, and Southern Music, Brussels.
    - Le Mal de dents
      Words by V. Scotto and Gitral, music by Vincent Scotto. Paris: Dufrenne, Editeur, n.d. (early 20th cent.). "Repertoire Mayol."
    - Le Malade et le médecin: duo comique
      Words by Ches. Voizo, music by B. Vallet. No indication of publisher. Dated in pencil 1838. Cover lithograph of a doctor at the home of a male patient.
    - La Maladie de Poilaudos
      Monologue by G. Brandimbourg. Paris: Vve. Léon Hayard, n.d. Cover image of a Major and sick Zouave.
    - La Manicure
      Monologue by Marcel Contandin. Paris: E. Bosuquet, n.d. Performed by Fernand Sined and by a list of others.
    - Un Mariage raté
      Monologue by Emile Carré. Paris: Eveillard and Jacquot, Editeurs, n.d. Printed text edited in pencil in French. Performed by Libert at la Scala and by Régiane at the Eden-Concert. Various scenes on the cover including a man using a big clyster as a weapon.
    - Une Mauvaise ordonnance: monologue comique
      Words by Saint-Gilles and Briolet, music by Saint-Gilles. Single sheet, probably extracted from a magazine, with words only. No publication information.
    - Les Maux comiques
      Monologue by Deroyre. Paris: Editions Francis Salabert, n.d,
    - Mazurka des microbes: chanson satirique
      Words by Louis Bousquet, music by L. Izoird. From Nos Chansons Françaises, No. 96, September 1928, pp. 238-239. Performed By Dalbret.
    - Le Médecin rigolo: consultation naive
      Words by A. Trébitsch and V. Tarault, music by Fél. Vargues. Paris: Georges Ondet, Editeur, n.d. (early 20th cent.). "Repertoire Resse." Sung by Mme. Debernay at the Ambassadeurs and by Resse at the Parisiana.
    - Le Meilleur remède: monologue
      By Abron de Cangogis (Baron de Sigognac). Paris: Pêle-Mêle-Edition, n.d. Series "Monologues pour Jeunes Gens," No. 7.
    - Messieurs les dentistes
      Words by Eugène Lemercier, music by Roger Berville. Extract from Nos Chansons Françaises, No. 136, January 1932, pp. 15-16.
    - Microbiana: scène comique
      Words by Gerny and Briollet, music by A. Gramet and Briollet. Paris: Emile Benoit, Editeur, n.d. (early 20th cent.). Performed by Vaunel at the Alhambra. List of other performers and theaters.
    - La Microbomanie: march chantée
      Words by Edouard Guy, music by Paul Leconte. Paris: M. Labbé, Editeur, n.d. Performed by Charlus.
    - Le Mollet de Rose: rondeau
      Words by Lucien Delormel, music by Félicien Vargues. Paris: G. Ondet, n.d. Performed by Yvette Guilbert at the Concert Parisien, and by Mlle. Anna Thibaud at la Scala. Color lithograph image of a young pharmacist and a young woman in a pharmacy.
    - Mon pére: monologue Marseillais
      Words by Saint-Gilles and Doumel. From Recueil de Douze Monologues, No. 18. This issue is titles "Histoires & blagues Marseillaises créées par Doumel." Paris: Les Editions Jean Picot, n.d. (early 20th cent.). Other monologues in this issue with medical themes include "Chez le Docteur Voronoff" (on glandular transplants for rejuvenation), and "Parisiens et Marseillais."
    - Mon pharmacien: chansonette comique
      Cover and first page of music only. Words by Vylé and Pliébus, music by Edouard Jouve. Paris: Edouard Jouve, Editeur, n.d. "Répertoire Gaudet." Performed by Mlle. Gaudet at the Eldorado. List of other performers and theaters.
    - Monsieur le pharmacien: duo enfantin
      Words by Mme A. Blanc-Péridier, music by Mme. J. Fonssagrives. Extracted from Nos Chansons Françaises, No. 72, September 1926, pp. 234-235. Song about a sick doll.
    - Neurasthéniqu'
      Words by Pousigue-Meyrel, music by Hugh-Cannon. Paris: Smyth, Editeur, c. 1901. "Chanson sur les motifs de I Hates to Get Up Early in the Morn."
    - Oh! ces microbes!
      Monologue by Abron de Cangogis (Baron de Sigognac). Paris: Pêle-Mêle-Edition, n.d. From series "Monologues pour jeunes gens."
    - Oh! J'ai une puce
      Words and music by Roggees. Paris: Baudot, Editeur, n.d. (19th cent.). Performed by Paulus at la Scala. Chromolithograph of a photographer adjusting a camera on a tripod, while the subject, a young woman, can't stand still because she has an itch (a flea).
    - L'Ombre: couplets
      By F. De Flotow. Paris: C. Joubert, n.d. From the series "Lyre Française."
    - L'Opération du Saint-Esprit: monologue comique en vers
      By Latapie. Paris: H. Billy, Successeur de L. Baudot, n.d.
    - Ousque ça s'met
      Words by Bin. Lebreton and F. Desplantes, music by J. Arnauld. Paris: Emile Benoit, Editeur, n.d. (19th cent.). Cover lithograph of a young man and a young woman. The woman holds a "Clyso" pump.
    - Paris-Publicité
      By Victor Vallier. Paris: Editions Herpin, n.d. Words with indication of tunes to be played. Performed by Victor Vallier at the Noctambules and by Marcel Saget at the Petit Casino and the Européen. About the advertisements for products, including medical products, that the one can while riding on a train.
    - La Pharmacie en goguette
      Words by Léo Lelièvre and Fernand Dervyl, music by Alcib Mario and Naudin-W. Paris: Charles Mayol, c. 1908. "Répertoire Félix Mayol." Performed by Mayol at the Ambassadeurs.
    - Le Pharmacien occupé: scène comique a deux personages
      Words by Belhiatus, music by Hermand-Brun. Paris: Emile Benoit, n.d. Piano music for entry and exit, and spoken dialogue. Performed by M.M. Chavat and Girier at la Scala. Cover image of a wealthy man at a pharmacist's counter.
    - Le Pharmacien occupé
      Words by Belhiatus, music by Hermand-Brun. Words only, extracted from Les Chansons Illustrées, 2e série, No. 8. Performed by Chavat and Girier at la Scala.
    - Pierrot - médecin
      Words by Hector Sombre, music by Gaston Maquis. In Le Rêve du Chanteur, No. 46, n.d. Honoré Pion, Imprimeur-Editeur.
    - La Pilule secrête
      Words by Delormel and Garnier. Paris: Répertoire moderne, n.d. Music for entry and exit and words for a monologue. Cover lithograph of of a wealthy older man seated and another man standing, perhaps offering a pill.
    - Les Pilules groscolard
      Monologue with words by Sim. Paris: Marcel Labbé, n.c. (20th cent.). Performed by Charlus.
    - La Pipe de Commandant
      Words by Villemar-Delormel, Music by Ch. Pourney. Paris: Emile Benoit, Editeur, n.d. Performed by Mr. Garnier at the Alcazar and by Mr. Sulbac at the Ambassadeurs. Sheet music torn but not affecting words or music. Lithograph cover of the Commandant and a subordinate. The "pipe" is a "Clyso" pump.
    - Le Pochard médecin
      Words by Garofolo and Grinda, music by P. Codini. Marseilles: André Cidale, Editeur, n.d. Sold by Labbé in Paris. Performed by Grinda at the Ambassadeurs and Sardou at the Alcazar.
    - La Pommade capillaire: chanson "échevelée"
      Words and music by Jean de Kerlecq. From La Bonne Chanson, 5e année, no. 51, January 1912, pp. 12-13.
    - La Poudre d'escampette: monologue militaire
      Words by Paul Lorans. Paris: J. Ferrand, Editeur, n.d.
    - Le Professeur d'anatomie
      Words by Léon Stollé, music by R. Pandéra. Paris: Editions Marcus, n.d. (20th cent.). "Causerie radiophonique de Stollé." Music and monologue. Image of a professor pointing at a skeleton.
    - La P'tite pharmacienne
      Words by Rimbault, music by Christiné. Paris: P. H. Christiné, n.d. (20th cent.). Performed by Polin at la Scala. About a woman pharmacist.
    - La Puce: chansonette Tyrolienne
      Words by L. Marcel, music by Jules Lacoustène. Paris: G. Ondet, Editeur, n.d. Performed by Velly at the Eldorado. Cover image of a man and woman in bed accosted by a huge flea.
    - Remède unique: scène comique
      Words by Chicot, music by M. Peyrla. Paris: Emile Benoit, n.d.(early 20th cent.). Performed by Vaunel and Constantin.
    - Le Remède universel
      Monologue by Georges Goudon. Lyon: Max Orgeret, Editeur, n.d. [early 20th cent.]. Image of a huckster promoting a bottled remedy to a group of people.
    - Le Renard du Sacré-Coeur: légend fin de siècle
      Words by A. Poupay, music by Emile Spencer. Paris: Albert Repos, n.d. (ca. 1900). Performed by Sulbac at the Eldorado. Colored image of a fox surrounded by a group of people in a church. Some, including a general and a clergyman, are attacking the fox. One man is using a clyster as a weapon. A young woman is holding holding up her skirt.
    - R'gardez-y mais n'y touchez pas
      Words by Henri Min, music by Ch. Sebye. Paris: Emile Benoit, Editeur, n.d. Performed by Jules Hervier at the winter Alcazar, and by Guichard at the summer Alcazar. Image of a man and a woman walking away from a pharmacy shop, but not touching or looking at each other.
    - Le Rire médecin: monologue comique
      By Eugène Lemercier. Paris: Marcel Labbé, Editeur, n.d. When the doctor bends over the patient in bed, his hairpiece attaches to a cone ("cornet') glued with a substance to catch insects. The toupé flies off the doctor's bald head and the patient is cured by laughter. Image of this scene on the cover.
    - Les Saints de Paris: ou le calendrier fin de siècle
      Words by V. Damien, music by A. Vieillot. Paris: F. Bigot, Editeur, n.d. (ca. 1900). Performed by Caudieux at the Petit-Casino. One Saint is Saint Clyso, with reference to the "Clsyo" (clyster) pump. Another is Saint Corset. Color lithograph on cover illustrating all the "Saints."
    - Sérénade au pharmacien
      Words by Briollet and Gerny, music by Del-Fragson. Paris: Répertoire Français, n.d. (early 20th cent.). Performed by Fragson at the summer Alcazar.
    - Sérénade de l'apothicaire
      Words by Emile André and T. Bruet, music by A. Guyon fils [Guyon, Jr.]. Paris: Bathlot-Joubert, Editeurs, n.d. Color lithograph cover showing an apothecary in love holding a huge clyster.
    - La Sérénade du potard
      Words by E. Rayel and A. Moullet, music by L. Lust. Paris: F. Bigot, Editeur, n.d. Performed by E. C. Luciani at the Concert Parisien and by Louis Chevalier at the Moulin-Rouge. Color image shows a young pharmacist holding a clyster and serenading a woman on a balcony. The woman throws the contents of a chamberpot at him.
    - Sirup Typhon (Lily the Pink)
      French words by Richard Anthony, English version by Norman, McGear, and McGouch. London: Noel Gay Music Co., Ltd, c. 1968. S.A.C.E.M., Belgium, has French and Belgian rights. This item is the French version. The Sirop Typhon is a panacea. Cover image of a strong man flexing his muscles, with a waiter bringing him Syrop Typhon. Recorded on Tacoun records and distributed by Pathé-Marconi.
    - Spécialités pharmaceutiques
      Words by R. Devilliers, music by Georges Briez. Paris: Publications Raoul Breton & Cie, c. 1933. Performed by René Devilliers.
    - Le Squelette: méditation
      Words by Edmond Goupil, music by Auguste Olivier. Paris: F. Gauvin, Editeur, n.d. Performed by Jules Léter at the Eldorado. Cover image of a Vesalius-like bearded man contemplating a skull set on top of Renaissance-era books. A scale and alchemical apparatus are also in the room.
    - Le Temps des grippes
      Words by Jules Jouy to be sung to the tune, "Le Temps des cerises." Extracted from La Bonne Chanson, No. 41, March 1911, p. 87
    - Totor et Plon-Plon: chanson de circonstance
      Words and music by "M***." Paris: Tralin, Editeur de Musique, n.d. (19th cent.). Humorous song about the Emperor vs. the French Republic. Cover image of a Napoleonic soldier carrying a clyster and with a chamberpot draped from his neck down his back. He is conversing with a man in the form of a bee.
    - La Tubercule.....Rose: chansonette militaire
      Trimmed cover only. Words by Jules Combe, music by Eug. Gavel. No information on publication. Advertisement on back for music published by Bloch et Valsien, successors to E. Guéprotte, Paris. "Répertoire Bach."
    - Les Tyroliennes de la vie: Scène comique imitative
      Words by Blondelet and Baumaine, music by Charles Malo. Paris: Feuchot, Editeur, n.d. Verses about the life of a man at 20, 40, and 60. Lithograph cover illustrating scenes from the song and spoken verses. Performed by Mr. Bruet at the Eldorado and by Mr. Desroches at the summer Alcazar.
    - Le Vieillard mourant
      Words by Eugène Hanappier, music by F. Masini. Paris: J. Delahante, Editeur de Musique, n.d. (early-mid 19th cent.). Lithograph cover showing a daughter kneeling at the bed of her dying father.
    - Villes de'eaux
      By Gaston Secrétan. From La Bonne Chanson, 4e année, No. 66, August 1911, pp. 234-235. On water treatments at a spa.
    - Les Visites de docteur
      Monologue by René Esse and Gerny. From Les Chansons Illustrées, No. 14, n.d. Originally published by E. Benoit. Performed by Vaunel at the Eldorado.
    - Vous vous plaignez François, vous avez tort
      Words by E. Gerny and Reyar, music by Emile Duhem. Paris: Emile Benoit, Editeur, n.d. (19th cent.). Performed by Arnaud at the Eden-Concert. Cover image of a man (presumably the singer) dressed as a matron. Smaller images including one of a woman attacking a man with a clyster.
    - Y a qu' des microbes!..: monologue comique
      Words by Léo Lelièvre and J. Mathis, music by G. Burgairolles. Paris: E. Lacroix, Editeur, n.d. (20th cent.). Words only. Performed by Dranem at the Eldorado.
- Individual songs in other languages; Argentine tangos, 3.
  - El 606: tango medicinal para la curación de todo mal (Box 10)
    Composed by Reynaldo Sales de Araujo. Buenos Aires: Alfred O. Francalanci, n.d. (early 20th cent.). "Dedicado á los boticarios." Image of a doctor injecting a patient. 606 refers to physician Paul Ehrlich's 606th trial, which resulted in Salvarsan, a remedy for syphilis.
  - Anatomia: Tango Caracteristico para Piano
    By Eduardo Aroley. "Dedicado a los distinguidos Doctor Ricardo Rodriguez Villegas y Moises Benchetrit." Buenos Aires: Breyer Hnos., n.d. (early 20th cent.).
  - El Anatomista: Tango
    By Vicente Greco. "Dedicato a los practicantes Internos de los Hospitales de la Capital, con motivo del tercer Baile del Internado, 21 Septiembre de 1916." Buenos Aires: Breyer Hnos., ca. 1916.
  - Apotheken Kantate
    By Fritz Kochinsky. Wilhelmshaven: Otto Heinrich Noetzel, c. 1957. For three male voices and piano.
  - Apotheken Kantate
    Composed by Fritz Koschinsky. Wilhelshaven, Germany: Otto Heinrich Noetzel, c. 1958. For three male voices and chamber orchestra. Full score.
  - Bicarbonato: Tango Curativo
    By Aleardo Battisti. Buenos Aires: Breyer Hermanos, n.d. (early 20th cent.). "Al Distinguido Medico y Amigo Dr Enrique Feinmann."
  - Clinicas
    Tango by R. Alberto Lopez Buchardo. Buenos Aires: Breyer Hermanos, n.d. [ca. 1914]. "Dedicado a los Practicantes del Hospital Clinicas."
  - Doctor Klaus Polka
    Composed by E. Winterberg. Hamburg: Ludwig Hoffmann, n.d. (19th cent.).
  - Doktor Panschers Pillenkur
    "Humoristisches Gesamtspiel" by Henry Feldow-Bechly, music by Wilhelm Wolff. Muhlhausen i. Thur., Germany: G. Danner, n.d. (19th cent.).
  - Der Kranke Onkel: Humoristische Ensemblescene für 4 Herren
    Words by Johann Wendler, music by Otto Teich. Liepzig: Otto Teich Verlag, n.d. [1907].
  - El Opio
    Composed by Francisco Canaro. Buenos Aires: G. Ricordi & C., n.d. (early 20th cent.). "Tango milonga."
  - Púrguese: Tango
    Composed by Vicente De Cicco. Buenos Aires: Roque Gaudiosi. Copyright by the author, n.d. (early 20th cent.). Dedicated to Doctor Nicholás Capizzano.
  - Rawson: Tango
    Composed by E. Arolas. Buenos Aires: Breyer Hnos., n.d. (early 20th cent.). Color image of doctors on the cover. "Dedicado a los Doctores Pedro Sauré, Juan Carlos Aramburu y Cleto Santa Coloma."
  - Rawson: Tango
    Composed by E. Arolas. No publication information. Same cover image as previous item but in brown and white. No dedication statement.
  - Sequah-Marsch
    Composed by M. I. Nolen. Rotterdam: Gebr. Poot, n.d. (19th cent.). Image of a bonesetter and a line of patients with crutches.
  - El Termómetro: Tango
    Composed by José Martinez. Buenos Aires: Breyer Hnos., n.d. (early 20th cent.). Cover scene of doctor standing near a patient in a bed, and looking at the thermometer. "A los Doctores Luis Galdeano, Amadeo Carelli y Antonio M. González."
- Music advertising a product or practitioner, 4.
  - (Back-Bone Albert, "The Chiropractor") In Flanders Fields (Box 11)
    Words by John McCrae, music by Almon Eastman Field. Copyright 1919 by John Henry Albert. On back cover is an illustrated explanation, "What Chiropractic Is."
  - (Bayer AG) Dream Serenade: The Bayer Aspirin Radio Theme Song
    Composed by Gustave Haeschen. Title by Frank S. Houck, Ph.G. Copyright, 1932. Theme song from the Bayer Aspirin Program, "The American Album of Familiar Music," on the NBC Red Network.
  - (Bayer AG) Qué me importa!: Tango milonga
    Words and music by José Bohr. Published by Bayer, no date (1920s?), and advertising "Cafiaspirina."
  - (Beecham's Pills) The Beecham Waltz
    Composed by May Ostlere. London: Howard & Co., n.d. (late 19th cent.). Advertisement for Beecham's Pills on the back cover. See Series 6 for more music from Beecham's Pills, Ltd.
  - (Bile Bean Manufacturing Company) The Bile Bean March